# **Preston Culbertson**

### Curriculum Vitae

Phone: (352) 615-3003

Email: pculbert@caltech.edu

Website: https://its.caltech.edu/~pculbert

### **Education**

Stanford University PhD in Mechanical Engineering Advisor: Mac Schwager	2022
Stanford University MS in Mechanical Engineering	2020
Georgia Institute of Technology BS in Mechanical Engineering	2016

## **Work Experience**

California Institute of Technology	
Dooldoolough Calculan	

Postdoctoral Scholar 2022 - present Advisor: Aaron Ames

Caltech / NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory

NSTRF Visiting Technologist 2018 - 2021

Caltech / NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory

Graduate Student Intern 2017

## **Research Summary**

I am interested in building **collaborative** robots that can **understand and interact** with their environment, humans, and other robots. My primary research interests are **adaptive** and **learning-based control**, **manipulation and grasping**, and **multi-agent interaction and coordination** (especially without communication). My existing research threads are best summarized as:

- Decentralized, adaptive control for collaborative manipulation of unknown objects,
- Integrating learning-based perception methods into robot motion planning, and
- Fast, efficient discrete optimization for assembly, grasp, and motion planning.

### **Awards**

**RSS Pioneer**, Workshop for top early-career robotics researchers. *Robotics: Science and Systems Pioneers Workshop*, 2021.

**ICRA Best Manipulation Paper Award**, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation." *ICRA 2018*.

**ICRA Best Multi-Robot Systems Paper Finalist**, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation." *ICRA 2018*.

**NASA Space Technology Research Fellowship**, Awarded to 56 students in the US. *National Aeronautics and Space Administration*, 2018.

**NSF GRFP Honorable Mention**, National Science Foundation Graudate Research Fellowship Program, 2018.

Graduate School of Engineering Fellowship, Stanford University, 2016.

**Richard K. Whitehead Jr. Memorial Award**, Awarded to the top three graduating seniors in Mechanical Engineering. *Georgia Institute of Technology*, 2016.

**President's Scholarship**, "Full ride" merit scholarship awarded to top 50 incoming undergraduates, *Georgia Institute of Technology*, 2012.

## **Teaching Experience**

Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2022
Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2021
Graduate Teaching Assistant AA273: State Estimation and Filtering for Aerospace Systems	Spring 2018
Graduate Teaching Assistant  AA277: Multi-Robot Control, Communication, and Sensing	Winter 2018

## **Academic Publications and Presentations**

### **Iournal Articles**

1. M. Adamkiewicz\*, T. Chen\*, A. Caccavale, R. Gardner, **P. Culbertson**, J. Bohg, and M. Schwager, "Vision-only robot navigation in a neural radiance world," in *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2021. *Accepted*.

<sup>\*</sup> indicates equal contribution

- 2. A. Cauligi, **P. Culbertson**, E. Schmerling, M. Schwager, B. Stellato, M. Pavone, "CoCo: Online mixed-integer control via supervised learning," in *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2021.
- 3. **P. Culbertson**, J.-J. Slotine, M. Schwager, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation of rigid bodies," in *IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)*, 2021.

#### **Conference Papers**

- 1. **P. Culbertson**, S. Bandyopadhyay, A. Goel, P. McGarey, and M. Schwager, "Multirobot assembly scheduling for the Lunar Crater Radio Telescope on the far-side of the moon," in *IEEE Aerospace Conference*, 2022. *Accepted*.
- 2. C. Chen, **P. Culbertson**, M. Lepert, M. Schwager, and J. Bohg, "TrajectoTree: Trajectory optimization meets tree search for planning multi-contact dexterous manipulation," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, 2021.
- 3. A. Cauligi\*, **P. Culbertson**\*, B. Stellato, D. Bertsimas, M. Schwager, and M. Pavone, "Learning mixed-integer convex optimization strategies for robot planning and control," in *Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)*, 2020.
- 4. **P. Culbertson**, S. Bandyopadhyay, and M. Schwager, "Multi-robot assembly sequencing via discrete optimization," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, 2019.
- 5. **P. Culbertson** and M. Schwager, "Decentralized adaptive control for collaborative manipulation," in *International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)*, 2018. **Best Manipulation Paper Award.**
- 6. P. Slade, **P. Culbertson**, Z. Sunberg, M. Kochenderfer, "Simultaneous active parameter estimation and control using sampling-based Bayesian reinforcement learning," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robotics and Systems (IROS)*, 2017.

#### Workshops and Invited Presentations

- 1. Stanford Machine Learning and Statistics Lunch (Seminar), *Collaborative Manipulation in the Wild*, 2022.
- 2. Ames-Burdick Group Meeting, Caltech (Seminar), Collaborative Manipulation in the Wild, 2021.
- 3. ASE 389: Modeling Multi-Agent Systems, UT Austin (Guest Lecture), *Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation*, 2021.
- 4. NASA Technology Integration Meeting on Lunar Excavation and Construction, *Collaborative Manipulation for Space Exploration and Construction*, 2021.
- 5. Learning Meets Combinatorial Algorithms Workshop, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), CoCo: Learning Mixed-Integer Convex Optimization Strategies for Robot Planning and Control, 2020.

- 6. Bay Area Machine Learning Symposium, Learning Mixed-Integer Convex Optimization Strategies for Robot Planning and Control, 2020.
- 7. AA277: Multi-Robot Control, Communication and Sensing (Guest Lecture), *Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation*, 2019.
- 8. Conference on Learning for Dynamics and Control (L4DC), *Decentralized Adaptive Control of Hamiltonian Systems*, 2019.
- 9. Bay Area Robotics Symposium (BARS), Decentralized Adaptive Control for Collaborative Manipulation, 2017.

### **Professional Activities**

#### Professional Service

- 1. Co-organizer, Workshop on Motion Planning with Implicit Neural Representations of Geometry, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2022.
- 2. Faculty Committee, RSS Pioneers Workshop, Robotics: Science and Systems, 2022.
- 3. Program Committee, Robot Learning Workshop: Self-Supervised and Lifelong Learning, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

#### Review Activities

- 1. American Control Conference
- 2. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)
- 3. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)
- 4. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)
- 5. Field Robotics
- 6. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (R-AL)
- 7. IEEE Robotics and Autonomous Systems
- 8. IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence (T-AI)
- 9. IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (T-AC)
- 10. IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)

#### Mentorship Activities

- 1. Graduate Research Mentor, Multi-Robot Systems Lab, 2018-present.
- 2. After-School Tutor, S.A.Y. Yes! Center, 2015-2016.
- 3. Programming Workshop Leader, Vine City Code Crew, 2015-2016.